Guide to the New England Society in the City of New York Records 1805-1941 MS 3113
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Financial Records, 1824-1937
  - Checkbook, 1928-1929 (Offsite-box 20, Volume SN 4)
  - Checks (2 folders), 1919-1924 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Dinner payment book, 1890-1898 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 58)
  - Dinner payment book, 1893 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
  - Dinner payment book, 1895 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
  - Dues collection book, 1824-1830 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 10)
  - Dues collection book, 1825-1837 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 11)
  - Dues collection book, 1829-1847 (Offsite-box 20, Volume SN 18)
  - Dues collection book, 1836-1847 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 12)
  - Dues collection book, 1850-1860 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 13)
  - Dues collection book, 1850-1860 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 22)
  - Dues collection book, 1850-1860 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 23)
  - Dues collection book, 1860-1870 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 15)
  - Dues collection book, 1870-1880 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 17)
  - Due collections book, 1880-1890 (Offsite-box 27, Volume SN 20)
  - Dues collection book, 1890-1900 (Offsite-box 27, Volume SN 19)
  - Dues collection book, 1893-1894 (Offsite-box 19, Volume 57)
  - Dues correspondence (2 folders), 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 14-15)
  - Dues correspondence (7 folders), 1929-1937 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1-7)
  - Finance Committee reports, 1909-1921 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
  - Finance Committee reports, 1926-1928 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13)
  - Investment Record, 1917-1920 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN 1)
  - Plymouth Church Fund records (3 folders), 1895 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11-13)
    The Church fund was a fundraising campaign launched by the New England Society to help maintain the First Parish Church of Plymouth and preserve its documents. The First Parish Church of Plymouth was founded by Puritans of the English town of Scrooby in 1606 and the congregation emigrated to the Americas in 1620. Includes a subscription book for donors.
  - Treasurer's memos, 1834-1835 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's memos, 1895-1900 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 14)
  - Treasurer's memos, 1907-1909 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 15)
  - Treasurer's memos (2 folders), 1909-1910 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Treasurer's memos, 1917-1919 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 17)
  - Treasurer's memos, 1917-1920 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 22)
  - Treasurer's memos, 1921-1924 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 27)
  - Treasurer's memos (4 folders), 1924-1929 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5-8)
  - Treasurer's memos, 1935-1936 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer's memos, 1938 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 15)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1913-1917 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1918-1922 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11)
  - Vouchers (3 folders), 1836-1870 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Vouchers of J.P. Morgan (3 folders), 1877-1884 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4-6)
    These are vouchers from J.P. Morgan's time as Treasurer of the New England Society. Additionally includes a small notebook that kept track of all vouchers.
  - Vouchers (6 folders), 1885-1899 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7-12)
  - Voucher Book (Blank), 1890s (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
  - List of Vouchers, 1894 December-1918 August (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN 5)
  - List of Vouchers, 1918 September-1928 October (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN 6)
  - List of Vouchers, 1928 November-1934 December (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN 2)
  - Vouchers (17 folders), 1897-1915 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1-17)
  - Vouchers (14 folders), 1916-1930 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1-14)
  - Vouchers (15 folders), 1931-1937 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1-15)
    Includes several vouchers for the purposes of an charitable annuity for Mrs. Gilbert Peckham, a teacher who had injured her ankle and was thus prevented from working. Mrs. Peckham left extensive notes on most of these vouchers, explaining her situation and gratitude to the New England Society.
- Series VI. Event Records, 1870-1922
  This series is organized into two subseries to reflect the different types of events which the New England Society held. The first subseries specifically covers material related to the Annual Dinner/Festival, while the other subseries covers materials from assorted dinners, dedications, and events.
  - Subseries VI.A. Annual Dinner and Festival, 1870-1913
    The subseries contains 21 volumes and loose material relating to material related to the Annual Dinner/Festival, including correspondence, guestbooks, invitation printing plates, the stenographer reports, and some of the copies of addresses given during the dinner, and applications for guests. Of particular note is the guests of these dinners, as the Society traditionally invited notable federal and state politicians, businessmen, industrialists, and other figures to their dinners.
    This subseries is organized chronologically.
    - Printing plates, 1870-1910 (Offsite-box 25)
      Approximately 10 printing plates used for the printing of invitations and menus for the Annual Dinner of the New England Society.
    - Guest book, 1889 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 60)
    - RSVP scrapbook, 1889 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 56)
    - Guest book, 1890s (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 59)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1892 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    - Guest book, 1892 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 61)
    - Guest book, 1893 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 55)
    - Dinner correspondence (2 folders), 1894 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2-3)
    - Guest book, 1894 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 62)
    - Guest book, 1895 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 63)
    - Guest book, 1896 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 64)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1897 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    - Dinner correspondence "official guests", 1897 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
    - Guest book, 1897 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 59)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1898 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
    - Seating arrangement, 1898 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
    - Guest book, 1898 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN 53)
    - Dinner dues collection book, 1898-1908 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 65)
    - Dinner stenographer reports, 1898, 1902-1903 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1899 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - Guest book, 1899 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 52)
    - Dinner correspondence (2 folders), 1900 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9-10)
      Includes letters with Woodrow Wilson, then President of Princeton, thanking the Society for inviting him.
    - Guest book, 1900 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 50)
    - Dinner correspondence (3 folders), 1901 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11-13)
    - Guest book, 1901 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 49)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1902 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1903 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2-3)
    - Guest book, 1903 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 47)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1904 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
    - Guest book, 1904 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 66)
    - Dinner Committee Documents, 1904-1905 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 16)
    - Dinner stenographer reports, 1904-1906 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
    - Dinner correspondence (2 folders), 1905 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Guest book, 1905 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 46)
    - Dinner correspondence (2 folders), 1906 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Guest book, 1906 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 48)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1907 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 9)
    - Guest book, 1907 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 51)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1908 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 10)
    - Dinner addresses and speeches, 1908 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 10)
      Includes remarks from Leonard Wood and Seth Low, the latter honoring Theodore Roosevelt, who was present at the 1908 dinner.
    - Guest book, 1908 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN 45)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1909 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 11)
    - Dinner stenographer reports, 1907-1909 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 8)
    - Dinner addresses and speeches, 1910 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 11)
      Includes the annual sermon, "The Puritan's Contribution Today," by Rev. Hugh Birckhead, "The Forefathers and the American Idea" by Darwin Kingsley, and additional addresses from James Thompson McCleary and President Thomas.
    - Dinner applications, 1910 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    - Dinner promotional material, 1910 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 18)
    - Dinner stenographer reports, 1910-1911 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9)
    - Dinner correspondence "official guests", 1910-1911 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
      Primarily includes correspondence with the official guests of the Annual Dinner, including correspondence with the US President, various governors, bankers, lawyers, among others.
    - Dinner correspondence, 1911 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
    - Dinner correspondence, 1912 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dinner correspondence "official guests", 1912 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
    - Dinner applications, 1913 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    - Dinner correspondence (3 folders), 1913 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5-7)
    - Dinner programs, 1913 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 10)
  - Subseries VI.B. Other Events, 1875-1922
    The subseries contains loose material related to all events hosted and sponsored by the New England Society other than their Annual Dinner/Festival, including sermons, lectures, book printings, and dedications. Of particular interest would be the Society's involvement in the creation of the Pilgrim Hall Portico, which was designed by the famous architecture firm McKim, Mead, and White.
    - Anniversary booklet, 1878 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
    - Fines Dinner records (5 folders), 1895-1899 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 15-19)
      Records of the annual "Fines" dinner held at the Union League, unrelated to the much larger and extravagant Annual Dinner.
    - Yearbook galley prints, 1898, 1904 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
    - Member's Entertainment documents, 1901 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4)
    - Member's Entertainment galley prints, 1901 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
    - Yearbook, 1908 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 14)
    - Pilgrim Monument Memorial Dedication, 1910 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 19)
    - Yearbook galley prints, 1910-1911, 1913 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
    - Yearbook, 1911 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 15)
    - Annual Sermons, 1910-1911 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 12)
      Sermons to members of the New England Society, from Hugh Birckhead (1910) and William Grosvenor (1911).
    - Annual Sermons, 1911-1912 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 13)
      Includes the annual sermons from William Pierce Merill (1911) and John Jowett (1912).
    - Commodore J.W. Miller Lecture, 1911 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 20)
      "New England's Interest in the Cape Cod Canal"
    - Facsimile correspondence (2 folders), 1912-1913 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 22-23)
      Correspondence primarily about the printing and distribution of two facsimile tracts, "The Puritans' Farewell to England Being 'the Humble Request'" (1630) and "The Abstract of the Laws of New England" (1641)
    - Bay Psalm Book correspondence, 1913 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 11)
      Correspondence contains discussion about the printing and dissemination of a New England Society copy of the Bay Psalm Book, the first book printed in North America which contained translations of the Bible's psalms in vernacular poetry.
    - Yearbook, 1913 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 16)
    - Yearbook correspondence, 1913-1914 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 17)
      Includes correspondence with members and libraries about the purchase, shipping and donation of copies of the 1913 yearbook.
    - Charles K. Bolton Lecture correspondence, 1913 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 21)
    - Pilgrim Hall Portico Dedication documents (5 folders), 1920-1922 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 12-16)
      Includes a specs report from McKim, Mead, and White, the famous architecture firm which the New England Society patronized for the design and construction of the Pilgrim Museum portico.